

BARBARA

DESIGN / ILLUSTRATION
ART DIRECTION
MANAGEMENT

July, 7, 2017

Dear Lola,

I was excited to see the Senior Designer listing show up on the Aquent site. I'm currently working with a client out of your Chicago office. I believe the multidisciplinary experience I've accumulated as a Senior Designer / Art Director aligns perfectly with the responsibilities laid out within this listing, making myself an excellent candidate for the position.

Working directly with large international companies such as Aramark, Kraft, Wish-bone, Dreyers, Microsoft, Starbucks, and Saks Fifth Avenue and being directly responsible for the development of and compliance with large-scale brand identity guidelines has given me possession of all the necessary skills and vision to help clients expand their on-line, print and overall brand presence. Samples of creative concepts and campaigns in a fun, edgy and very modern design style can be seen on my portfolio site at samanich.com.

I've efficiently collaborated with various development, sales and marketing teams, both on-site and remotely. I have many years of experience working as a freelance designer and never have trouble managing myself or my workload. Once chosen, I'll be available via Face- time, Skype and phone; an on-site meeting could even be arranged. Please call me directly at 480.227.9331 or email me at barbara@samanich.com to discuss this opportunity further.

Thank you for your time and consideration!

Sincerely,

Barbara Samanich

CONTACT

480.227.9331 barbara@samanich.com samanich.com

BARBARA

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Fine Arts Communications Design Minor in Fine Arts Kent State University

SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite expert
Microsoft Office
Traditional Illustration
Typography / Calligraphy
Project Management
Creative Diversity
Critical Thinking
Clear Communication

ACHIEVEMENTS

Juried in: 10' Tall Fenders 2017/18 COT Bike Month Art Apache Corridor Brand

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ARAMARK 2011 - 2017

ART DIRECTOR

Cut costs with concept and construction of a West Region Graphics DeptExecute and support corporate initiatives while filling regional gapsResponsible for all visual communications

Establish high standards via constructive guidance and management **Assist** marketing managers with effective advertising and communications **Clients** Include: Higher Ed West Region & Partners

SAMAMAMA APPAREL 2005 - 2011

FOUNDER / DESIGN DIRECTOR

Created the brand identity for and content of Samamama collections **Engaged** in all aspects of design from initial concept to finished product **Responsible** for all visual communications, including seasonal collections, branding, catalogs, photo-shoots and website

Assist production managers with effective graphics for print processes **Clients** Include: Equinox, Yoga Works, Core Power, Bikram Yoga, Cando

SAMMY ART 1990 - 2006

DESIGNER / ILLUSTRATOR

Grew a freelance operation into a successful studio

Designed with creative vision and unique design skills utilizing both traditional and digital illustration techniques

Helped increase Wish-Bone Salad Dressing's market share for 7+ years by designing and developing their brand identity for print and TV campaigns **Clients** Include: Lipton, Kraft, Wish-Bone, DMB, Dreyers, Microsoft, Scott Foresman Publishing, Wildflower Bakery, Pepsi, OPI

CONTACT





480.227.9331 barbara@samanich.com samanich.com